<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LanguageApp</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello World</string>
    <string name="riceTitle">RICE</string>
    <string name="appName">KRISHI SAHAYAK</string>
    <string name="harvesting">HARVESTING</string>
    <string name="irrigation">IRRIGATION</string>
    <string name="fertilizers_and_pesticides">Fertilizers and Pesticides</string>
    <string name="land_preparation_and_methods">LAND PREPARATION AND METHODS</string>
    <string name="soil_requirements">SOIL REQUIREMENTS</string>
    <string name="riceSoilRequirements">"Rice farming can be done on a different variety of soil like as silts, loams, gravels, acidic and alkaline soils. The deep fertile clayey (rich in organic matter) and loamy soils are considered as an ideal soil or growing rice crop. In rice, farming Propagation is done through rice seeds. "</string>
    <string name="riceClimatic">Rice is a crop of tropical climate. However, it is also grown successfully in humid to sub-humid regions under subtropical and temperate climate. Rice is cultivated in almost all types of soils with varying productivity. Under high temperature, high humidity with sufficient rainfall and irrigation facilities, rice can be grown in any type of soil.</string>
    <string name="riceFertilizers"></string>
    <string name="riceFertilizer">* Chemical Fertilizers Nitrogen - 100 kg Phosphorus - 50 kg Potash - 50 kg * Micronutrients Zinc Sulphate - 20 kg Iron Sulphate - 12 kg Weedicides (Pre-emergence): 1. Butachlor 50 EC, 1 lt/acre (300 ltrs of water) 2. Saathi (Phyrazosulphuran Ethyl 100g/acre in 300 ltrs of water) http://www.rkmp.co.in/sites/default/files/ris/rice-state-wise/Status%20Paper%20on%20Rice%20in%20Karnataka.pdf</string>
    <string name="riceHarvesting">Harvesting rice consists of the basic operations which can be done in individual steps or in combination using a combine harvester. These include:  Reaping - cutting the mature panicles and straw above ground Threshing - separating the paddy grain from the rest of cut crop Cleaning - removing immature, unfilled, non-grain materials Hauling - moving the cut crop to the threshing location Field drying - leaving the cut crop in the field and exposing it to the sun for drying (optional) Stacking/piling - temporarily storing the harvested crop in stacks or piles (optional) Bagging - putting the threshed grain in bags for transport and storage Traditional harvesting activities such as field drying and stacking/piling are not recommended because they can lead to rapid quality deterioration and increased harvest losses.  Besides these, a variety of other activities can be included in harvesting such as gathering, reaping (gathering standing grain by cutting), bundling, and various forms of transporting the crop and grain.</string>
    <string name="riceIntro">"Rice is the processed form of paddy. Along with the husk, it is called paddy. Paddy cultivation is a complex process right from land preparation to harvesting of crops. Rice is a staple food in most parts of the world. But, with time there is a shortage of space and increase in demand for rice and other staple crops. So, cultivating rice is a very successful business. Reference: www.knowfarming.com Rice growing seasons and regions Major rice growing areas of the state can be broadly classified into two seasons, viz., kharif (June-July) and summer (January-February). In all the six rice growing ecosystems, Kharif sowing is common while during summer season the crop is cultivated mainly in the irrigated maidan areas of north and south. In the tank-fed areas, the crop is taken up late in the season (August-September) depending upon the monsoon showers. In coastal area, one can see a specific situation where a second crop is sown in September-October and harvested in JanuaryFebruary and the third crop is cultivated between December-January and March-April. In each district, nearly 60-80 per cent of the total area is covered during Kharif (wet) season while the remaining area is occupied in late Kharif and summer (dry) season. "</string>
    <string name="riceIrrigation">Paddy crop is strongly influenced by water supply. Water should be kept standing in the field throughout the growth period. In water scarcity areas, saturated soil in a chemical reduced stage is desirable. The characteristics of flooded soil which are conducive to high yields are: (i) greater availability of nutrients such as phosphorus, iron and manganese, (ii) suppression of weed competition, (iii) elimination of moisture stress as a limiting factor, (iv) micro-climate favourable to crop production.  Excess / limited / no water leads to reduction in yield. Rice a semi - aquatic plant requires near submergence Submergence helps in - suppressing weed growth  and more availability of certain nutrients Daily consumptive use of rice is 6 - 10mm Total water requirement of rice is 1200 - 1400 mm 2000 - 3000 litres of water required to produced 1kg of rice Highly saline and brakish water not good for irrigation Application of FYM or incorporation of green manures reduce adverse effects of excess salts Application of FYM or compost or green manures increases water holding capacity of light textured soils and thus saving of water Thorough puddling creates impermeable layer which reduces deep percolation losses Perfect leveling maintains uniform depth of water throughout field Maintenance of water depths in field as recommended for high water use efficiency and yield</string>
    <string name="riceLandPreparation">"There are basically three methods for land preparation in rice cultivation. The dry, semi-dry and Wet. •\tDry and Semi-dry system Generally, dry and semi-dry rice cultivation systems depend on the rain and it does not have complementary irrigation facilities. These two systems require good tilth land. Before sowing and planting uniformly apply farm yard manure (FMY)/compost for 2 weeks to 4 weeks. In this dry and semi-dry system seed should be sown by the drilling or broadcasting method. In drill sowing method row to row space is 20 cm to 25 cm. The dry and semi-dry system seed should be sown by the drilling or broadcasting method.The Drill Sowing method row to row space is 20 cm to 25 cm. References: https://agrifarmingtips.com "</string>
    <string name="rice_climatic_requirements">CLIMATIC REQUIREMENTS</string>
    <string name="horsegram">HORSEGRAM</string>
    <string name="horsegramIntro">Horse gram is one of the oldest pulse crops cultivated and consumed in India since centuries whose botanical name is “Macrotyloma uniflorum” and known as “hurule” in kannada. Horse gram is mainly cultivated in south India. Horse gram can be used in cooking’s and can be eaten as fresh sprouts. This grain is packed with high protein and this why race horses are fed with this pulse gram and became “horse gram”. This crop is mostly grown in dry lands. As these beans are having great nutrition values, these are uses as cattle field.</string>
    <string name="horsegramClimatic">Basically, both tropical and sub tropical climatic conditions are suitable for horse gram cultivation. This grain crop is a drought resistant, so mainly this crop is cultivated in low rainfall areas. The farmers cultivate this crop as rainfed crop in dry agricultural lands. The crop requires low to moderate annual rainfall of 500 mm to 700 mm. The optimum temperature for its growth is 20°C to 34°C.</string>
    <string name="horsegramSoilRequirements">Horse gram can be cultivated on wide range of soils. However, black cotton soils, deep red loam and clay loam paddy soils are the best for its cultivation. Even stony soils can be used for its cultivation. The greatness of horse gram crop is, it can be cultivated in poor soils where other crops don’t grow. Highly acidic or alkaline soils are not suitable for its cultivation. If the cultivation purpose is for quality seed production, soils with neutral pH must be selected. Adding organic matter in the soil leads to production of vigorous seed.</string>
    <string name="horsegramLandPreparation"><![CDATA[The seeds should be shown @1.5cm to 2cm depth with a plant to plant distance of 10cm and 30cm between rows. Land should be prepared to the fine tilth by giving 3 or 4 ploughs. Weeds and previously grown crops leaves and stems should be cleared in the field. Based on the cultivation practices, field should be made with 1 feet wide ridges & furrows (or) make beds and channels of 4 feet x 6 feet. Application of well rotten farm yard manure (FMY) will result in vigorous growth of the seeds.]]></string>
    <string name="horsegramFertilizer">5 to 6 tonnes of well rotten farm yard manure or compost should be added along with basal application of 20 to 22 kg of urea, 60 to 65 kg of super phosphate per acre land.</string>
    <string name="horsegramIrrigation">To produce a quality seeds, horse gram field must be monitored regularly for any water stress or drought conditions. Frequent irrigations should be given to keep the soil moisture, In case of water stress, this crop produces low vigor hardy small seeds and yield will be less due to flower shedding. Irrigation should be given immediately after sowing the seeds. Next life irrigation should be given on 3rd day. Subsequent irrigations should be carried out whenever the field becomes dry or on need basis. Make sure to irrigate the field especially at the time of flowering, pod forming and seed development stages.</string>
    <string name="jowarTitle">JOWAR</string>
    <string name="jowarIntro"><![CDATA[Jowar is one of the important food and fodder cereal crops cultivated across India, Sorghum popularly known as “Jola” in karnataka. The advantage of this cereal crop is that it can be cultivated in both Kharif and Rabi season. Jowar is the 5th most important cereal crop in the world after rice, wheat, maize & barley . The nutritional value of sorghum is same as of that of corn and that is why it is gaining importance as livestock feed. Sorghum (or) Jowar is also used for ethanol production, producing grain alcohol, starch production, production of adhesives and paper other than being used as food and feed for livestock. Jowar (or) Sorghum cultivation is gaining popularity due to its nature of extreme drought tolerance. Sorghum is very nutritious just like corn and can be used as green fodder, dry fodder, hay or silage.]]></string>
    <string name="jowarClimatic">Basically jowar or sorghum is a tropical crop. It thrives well at a temperature between 25°C and 32°C but below 16°C is not good for the crop. Jowar crop requires rainfall about 40 cm annually. Jowar is extreme drought tolerant crop and recommended for dry regions. Too much of moist and pro longed dry conditions are not suitable for jowar cultivation.</string>
    <string name="jowarSoilRequirements">Sorghum or Jowar crop adapts wide range of soils but grows well in sandy loam soils having good drainage. Soil pH range of 6 to 7.5 is ideal for its cultivation and better growth. The main field should be ploughed and leveled to fine tilth for weeds free sowing.</string>
    <string name="jowarLandPreparation">One should avoid rocky field and 1 to 2 ploughings followed by 2 crosswise harrowing are required to prepare a good seed bed. As the Sorghum or Jowar crop does not tolerate water lagging, the field should be prepared with well drainage.</string>
    <string name="jowarFertilizer">The main field should be added with 10 to15 tone of Farm Yard Manure (F.Y.M) to make the soil rich in micro nutrients. At the time of sowing, basal application of 60:40:40kg N: P2O5-K2O should be applied. Should apply 35kg N/ha top dressing 1 month after sowing. 60 to 65 kg N per hectare should be applied In low rainfall and rain fed areas at sowing time. In Sulphur deficient soils, 45 to 60 kg Sulphur /ha should be added which not only improves biomass but also quality. For any other nutrient deficiencies, soil test should be done and accordingly, apply the manures and fertilizers at the time of soil preparation.</string>
    <string name="jowarIrrigation">If the crop is sown in monsoon time (July). it may require l to 3 irrigations depending upon rains. For summer crops, 6 to 7 irrigations may be carried out due to high temperature. In South India, Rabi season crops need about 4 to 5 irrigations.</string>
    <string name="cowpeaTitle">COWPEA</string>
    <string name="cowpeaIntro">Cowpea crop is a Kharif legume crop and is grown across India for seeds ,green pods, animal fodder and organic green manure.</string>
    <string name="cowpeaClimatic">Cow pea thrives very well in warm seasons not in cold and winter seasons. Areas, where rainfall is more than average is not suitable for Cowpea Farming.Cowpea crop requires and do well in moist weather.</string>
    <string name="cowpeaSoilRequirements">The time of sowing depends on type of crop. Spring season Cowpea crop: February to March. Kharif season Cowpea crop: May to June Rabi season Cowpea crop: October to November Cowpea can be cultivated in wide range of soils. They do very well in sandy and sandy loam soils. You should make sure the soil is rich in organic matter, adding Farm Yard Manure(FYM)will make the soil more fertile . The land should be prepared by giving five to six ploughings before planting the cowpea seeds.</string>
    <string name="cowpeaFertilizer">5 tonnes of well decomposed compost (Field Yard Manure ) is used in the main fields along with basal application of 45kg urea and 120kg super phosphate per acre.</string>
    <string name="cowpeaIrrigation">It all depends on type of season, if it is rainy season ,no water is given for the cowpea crop, before rainy season couple of irrigations are preferred in cowpea farming.</string>
    <string name="turTitle">TUR</string>
    <string name="turIntro">Its actual place of origin is very controversial as some people believe is to orginate in India while others say that red gram was found in the wild estate in Africa in regions of upper Nile and the coastal districts of Angola. From Africa it spread to other parts of the world and to India. Arhar is grown as annual but tur varieties grow like perennial plants. The plants are bushy, densely branched having a height of about 150 cm to 300 cm depending upon type and management practices. It bears tap root with well developed lateral or secondary roots that consist nodules on them like any other leguminous plants.</string>
    <string name="turClimatic">Arhar needs moist and warm weather during germination (30-350C), slightly lower temperature during active vegetative growth (20-25 0 C) but about 15-18 0 C during flowering and pod setting, however, at maturity it needs higher temperature of around 35-40 0C. Water logging, heavy rains, frost are very harmful for the crop. Hailstorm or rain at maturity damages the entire crop. The crop may be grown on any type of soil but sandy loam to clayey loam soils are supposed to be best. Soil must be very deep, well drained and free from soluble salts in them.</string>
    <string name="turFertilizer">As a practice the arhar crop is grown on marginal and sub-marginal lands of poor soil fertility status due to which the yield is found to be so poor that it does not give much profit. The crop is heavy feeder but due to symbiotic bacteria present in the root nodules, most of the required nitrogen is fixed from atmosphere, however, it needs heavy doses of phosphate. The crop grown from inoculated seeds needs lesser quantity of nitrogen as the plants emerged from treated seeds are well nodulated hence they have high nitrogen fixing capacity than the plants grown from untreated seeds. For raising an ideal crop it is required to apply about 25-30 kg N, 50-75 kg P2O5, 30 kg K2O (if the soil is poor in K) and 10-15 kg ZnSo4 in one hectare area. The entire dose of fertilizer should be basal placed at a depth of 12 to 15 cm or 7 to 10 cm below the seed layer in the same row.</string>
    <string name="turIrrigation">The crop is mostly grown rainfed but one light irrigation between flowering and pod filling stage increases the seed yield. In the event of drought or under aberrant weather condition the crop needs life saving or protective irrigation which is in addition to those mentioned earlier.</string>
    <string name="turLandPreparation">The land may be prepared as for most of the kharif legumes keeping in view that there are no bigger clods, established weeds and left over stubbles of the previous crop. The field should be thoroughly levelled so that there is no accumulation of water in the field. Treated seeds of suitable variety having high germination and high real value should be selected for sowing the crop. In irrigated condition the crop should be sown by giving one pre-monsoon irrigation at least a fortnight earlier than the first shower so that plans are well established during rainy season, however, under rainfed conditions the sowing may be done immediately after rains have started. Thus in no case the sowing should be delayed beyond last week of June. In case of diara lands which are prone to flood, the sowing should be done by mid of September. Line sowing by seed drill or malabasa at a depth of about 7-10 cm using a row to row spacing of 60-75 cm and plant to plant 15-20 cm is always better than broadcasting. About 10-15 kg high quality seed would be sufficient for one hectare area but it depends on variety and sowing time.</string>
    <string name="soil_health_mission">SOIL HEALTH MISSION</string>
    <string name="what_is_soil_health">What is Soil Health?</string>
    <string name="soilHealthIntro">Sustaining agricultural productivity depends on quality and availability of natural resources like soil and water. Agricultural growth can be sustained by promoting conservation and sustainable use of these scarce natural resources through appropriate location specific measures. The components of soils are mineral, organic matter, water and air, the proportions of which vary and together form a system for plant growth. Soils are studied and classified according to their use. Soil Testing is a part of the discipline of Fertilizer Use and Management.</string>
    <string name="soilHealthNutrientTitle">Nutrient Status of soils of Karnataka:</string>
    <string name="soilHealthNutrientIntro">"Intensive agriculture with introduction of improved varieties of seeds, application of fertilisers and assured irrigation has resulted in substantial growth in food grain production.  However, extensive use of fertilisers and use of improved varieties has resulted in greater mining of soil nutrients which intern resulted in depleting soil fertility, decline in water table, decrease in organic matter content and deterioration in soil health.    In 2012-13, Karnataka has consumed about 891.69 thousand tonnes  of Nitrogen, 389.64  thousand tonnes  of  P2O5 and   249.87 thousand tonnes K2O fertilizers at per ha consumption rate of 68.27 kg/ha of  N, 29.83 kg/ha of  P2O5, and 19.13 kg/ha of K2O fertilisers. Fertilizer consumption ratio has increased from 2.1:1.4:1 in 2009-10 to 3.6:1.6:1 in 2012-13.  "</string>
    <string name="soil_testing_programme">Soil Testing Programme</string>
    <string name="soilTestingIntro">There are 29 static soil testing laboratories functioning in Karnataka State with analyzing capacity of 2,00,000 soil samples per annum. District wise location is appended in Annexure III. The soil samples are analysed for pH, EC, Major nutrients like Available N, P, K, secondary nutrients like Sulphur and Magnesium and micronutrients such as Zn, Fe, Mn, Cu and Boron. Water samples are also analyzed for pH , EC, Sodium Absorption ratio (SAR), Ca, Mg, Co3, HCo3 , Cl2 to assess the quality of water for irrigation. Well qualified and experienced personnel are working as analysts to ensure the quality of analysis. Every year refresher training is arranged to the Analysts working in the laboratories to upgrade their knowledge and skill in soil and water analysis. The functioning of these Soil Health Centers (SHCs) are reviewed regularly every month by the concerned Joint Director of Agriculture at District level and also at Directorate of Agriculture, Bangalore.</string>
    <string name="the_soil_health_card">THE SOIL HEALTH CARD</string>
    <string name="soilHealthCardInfo">Soil health card is field-specific detailed report of soil fertility status and other important soil parameters that affect crop productivity. Besides, soil health, it also provides an advisory on soil test based use of fertilizers and amendments. State Government is planning to take the support of supplementary institutions for covering large number of holding to generate soil health cards. Their activity can be outsourced or the SHCs can be operated on a Public Private Partnership mode. Standard procedures for the operational work of sampling, analysis, information reports in soil health cards and distribution to farmers will be put in place by the State Government. Soils will be analysed for N, P, K, EC, pH , secondary nutrients and micro nutrients. Analysis of the massive scale of soil samples will be used to operationalise soil test based, District/Taluqa/Hobli/ Grampanchayat wise fertilisers, (organic and inorganic,) recommendation for supplementing deficiencies. District/ Taluqa/ Hobli/ Grampanchayat wise recommendations for various crops will make it easier to scale up dissemination to farmers and popularise various components of nutrient management for relevant crops. It is estimated that the cultivated area is 133.81 lakh hectares and there are about 78.32 lakh farm holdings in the state. To achieve the target in 2016-17 it is proposed to analyse 29.85 lakh soil samples for three years and 9.94 lakh soil sample per annum.</string>
    <string name="details_in_a_soil_card">Details in a Soil Card</string>
    <string name="detailsInASoilCardInfo">Details in a Soil Health Card i. Information regarding Soil Fertility ii. Dosage of fertilizer application in crops. iii. Information on soil amendments of saline or alkaline soil iv. Recommendation on integrated nutrient management.</string>
    <string name="pest_control_title">Preparation and use of natural fertilizers for Organic Crop Production</string>
    <string name="pestControlIntro">Organic farming is found to be more favorable for farmer. Production of crops without use of the chemical fertilizer and pesticide is called organic farming. In this method of cropping anything which is naturally available can be utilized other then chemical fertilizer and toxins e.g. (farm yard manure, green manure, natural salt without any chemical reaction). We can achieve our production goal if we use organic farming on scientific basis. It is also a wrong perception that organic farming decreases the yield. The worth of crop grown by organic method is more than that of chemical fertilizer and cost of production is also lesser. Positive effect is shown on the crops cultivated organically for a long period of time. Organic farming improves the physical, chemical and biological properties of the soil. Our soil health has been declined due to the prolonged usage of chemical fertilizers. Use of chemical pesticides resulted in killing of many beneficial bacteria and other microorganisms; on the other hand they have harmful effect on human beings and environment as well. Keeping all these factors under consideration organic farming is beneficial. Whereas, this idea is totally wrong that it can be done in developed and rich countries only. Generally people have a misconception that organic farming only means application of Farm Yard Manure to the soil. Though in reality it is just a part of organic farming and constitutes only 10 percent of the organic farming while the rest 90 percent comes from other sources. For example decomposition of FYM is absolutely necessary because carbon and nitrogen content in fresh manure are not in dissolved form and therefore cannot be utilized. Manure contains 60-90 percent carbon and 0.5-5 percent of nitrogen. In addition there is phosphorus along with other macro- and micronutrients.</string>
    <string name="list_of_some_organic_fertilizers_and_their_benefits">List of Some Organic Fertilizers and their Benefits</string>
    <string name="manure">Manure for the garden comes from cow, sheep, poultry and horses. Pretty self-explanatory. Manure is known as a “complete” fertilizer; it has a lot of organic matter, but is low in nutrients. Manures are most valuable as organic soil amendments and mulches. Note: Beware of using fresh manure as a fertilizer because it can burn plants.</string>
    <string name="bloodMeal">Blood meal is dried, powdered blood collected from cattle slaughterhouses. It’s such a rich source of nitrogen that gardeners have to be careful not to over-apply and burn the roots of their plants. Apply blood meal just before planting to stimulate green leafy growth.</string>
    <string name="selfishFertilizer">Shellfish fertilizer or shell meal is made from crushed bones or shells from crab or other shellfish. It is a great source of calcium in addition to phosphorus and many trace minerals. One benefit of shellfish fertilizer: it contains chitin which encourages the growth of organisms that inhibit harmful pest nematodes.</string>
    <string name="batguano">Bat guano is protected by caves from leaching, so nutrients are conserved. It is rich in soluble nitrogen, phosphorous and trace elements. Usually powdery, bat guano may be used any time of year as a top dressing or diluted in a tea and used as a foliar spray. South American seabird guano is among the world’s best. It is gathered off the rocks of arid sea islands, where rainfall and decomposition is minimal. As a result, seabird guano is very high in nitrogen, phosphorous and other nutrients. At Planet Natural, we offer all kinds of garden supplies, including guanos, which provide plant nutrients in a natural form.</string>
    <string name="rockPhosphate">Rock phosphate is a calcium or lime-based phosphate rock that is usually ground to the consistency of small crumbs. This rock powder contains over 30 percent phosphate and a large number of trace elements. Rock phosphate does not leach out of the soil, remaining unchanged until taken up by the roots. Greensand is an iron potassium silicate that gives the minerals in which it occurs a green tint. Mined from an ancient New Jersey sea bed deposit of shells, Greensand is rich in iron, potassium and numerous micronutrients. Fish emulsion is a partially decomposed blend of finely pulverized fish. It can smell, although some deodorized versions have been developed. Like blood meal, it should be used sparingly in order not to burn plant roots.</string>
    <string name="manureIntro">There are few things better for enriching the soil in your garden than plain old rotted manure. You can purchase bags of manure fertilizer at most garden centers or, if you have chickens, goats or rabbits as backyard pets, you can use their droppings, too. Rabbit droppings have the highest nitrogen content and can safely be added directly to soil, but droppings from other animals should be composted before use.</string>
    <string name="garlicIntro">Garlic spray acts as a deterrent, encouraging insects to move on to more appetizing plants. Unlike many other types of insecticidal garden sprays, garlic can safely be applied to the leaves of plants. Drop the cloves from an entire bulb of garlic into the blender along with two cups of water, puree until finely blended and set it aside for a day. Then, strain out the pulp, mix the garlic liquid with a gallon of water and add it to a sprayer.</string>
    <string name="eggShellIntro">Egg shells are a multi-purpose aid in the garden, acting as both fertilizer and pest repellant. Add crushed eggshells to the bottom of planting holes, particularly when planting tomatoes, peppers and eggplant, or dry them out and blend them into a fine powder and spread them around the base of plants. Placing crushed eggshells (with sharp edges intact) in a ring around the base of a plant will deter slugs, snails and cutworms.</string>
    <string name="manureTitle">MANURE</string>
    <string name="garlic_spray_insecticide">GARLIC SPRAY INSECTICIDE</string>
    <string name="egg_shells_as_pest_repellent">Egg Shells as Pest Repellent</string>
    <string name="coconut">COCONUT</string>
    <string name="cotton">COTTON</string>
    <string name="maize">MAIZE</string>
    <string name="rice">RICE</string>
    <string name="castor">CASTOR</string>
    <string name="ground_nut">GROUND-NUT</string>
    <string name="ragi">RAGI</string>
    <string name="sugarcane">SUGARCANE</string>
    <string name="sun_flower">SUN-FLOWER</string>
    <string name="cow_pea">COW-PEA</string>
    <string name="horse_pea">HORSEGRAM</string>
    <string name="jowar">JOWAR</string>
    <string name="sesame">SESAME</string>
    <string name="tur">TUR</string>
    <string name="crop_info">CROPS</string>
    <string name="soil_info">SOIL HEALTH</string>
    <string name="pest_control">PEST CONTROL</string>
    <string name="insurance">INSURANCE</string>
    <string name="faq">FAQ</string>
    <string name="ask_any_queries">Ask any Queries</string>
    <string name="natural_insecticides_and_pestisides">Natural Insecticides and pestisides</string>
    <string name="crop_security">Crop Security</string>
    <string name="check_the_info_about_crops">Check the info about crops</string>
    <string name="check_soil_health_info_here">Check Soil health info here</string>
    <string name="krishikannnada">A portal for Karnataka\'s unique agricultural knowledge and information exchange!</string>
    <string name="krishi_darshan_youtube_channel">Krishi Darshan Youtube Channel</string>
    <string name="krishi_jagattu_agriculture_technology">Krishi Jagattu : Agriculture Technology</string>
    <string name="e_krishi_university_of_agricultural_sciences_bangalore">e-krishi -University of Agricultural Sciences ,Bangalore</string>
    <string name="center_of_agricultural_media">Center of Agricultural Media</string>
    <string name="kisan">KISAN is getting larger In its 28th edition, it is \'the\' place to experience the present and future of Indian Agriculture</string>
    <string name="ask_us">Ask Us</string>
    <string name="about_us">ABOUT US</string>
    <string name="important_links">IMPORTANT LINKS</string>
    <string name="pradhan_mantri_fasal_bima_yojana">Pradhan Mantri Fasal Bima Yojana</string>
    <string name="pradhanMantriIntro">The new Crop Insurance Scheme is in line with One Nation – One Scheme theme. It incorporates the best features of all previous schemes and at the same time, all previous shortcomings/weaknesses have been removed. The highlights of this scheme are as under: • There will be a uniform premium of only 2percent to be paid by farmers for all Kharif crops and 1.5percent for all Rabi crops. In case of annual commercial and horticultural crops, the premium to be paid by farmers will be only 5percent. The premium rates to be paid by farmers are very low and balance premium will be paid by the Government to provide full insured amount to the farmers against crop loss on account of natural calamities. • There is no upper limit on Government subsidy. Even if balance premium is 90percent, it will be borne by the Government. • Earlier, there was a provision of capping the premium rate which resulted in low claims being paid to farmers. This capping was done to limit Government outgo on the premium subsidy. This capping has now been removed and farmers will get claim against full sum insured without any reduction. • The use of technology will be encouraged to a great extent. Smart phones will be used to capture and upload data of crop cutting to reduce the delays in claim payment to farmers. Remote sensing will be used to reduce the number of crop cutting experiments.</string>
    <string name="NationalCrop">National Crop Insurance Programme (NCIP) / Rashtriya Fasal Bima Karyakram (RFBK)</string>
    <string name="NationalCropIntro">NCIP is a Central Sector Scheme formulated by merging National Agricultural Insurance Scheme (NAIS), Pilot Weather Based Crop Insurance Scheme (WBCIS), Pilot Modified National Agricultural Insurance Scheme (MNAIS) and and Pilot Coconut Palm Insurance Scheme (CPIS). The scheme came into force from Rabi 2013-14 and covers all districts. Loanee farmers will be covered on compulsory basis under the component- scheme of NCIP notified by the concerned state, while non-loanee farmers will choose either MNAIS or WBCIS component. Private sector Insurers with adequate infrastructure and experience will be permitted to implement NCIP besides Agriculture Insurance company of India (AlC).</string>
    <string name="insuranceProducts">Insurance Products from Agriculture Insurance Company of India Limited (AIC)</string>
    <string name="insuranceProductsIntro">Insurance Products from Agriculture Insurance Company of India Limited (AIC) Agriculture Insurance Company of India Limited (AIC) has been formed at the behest of Government of India, consequent to the announcement by the then Hon\'ble Union Finance Minister in his General Budget Speech FY 2002-03 that, to subserve the needs of farmers better and to move towards a sustainable actuarial regime, it was proposed to set up a new Corporation for Agriculture Insurance AIC has taken over the implementation of National Agricultural Insurance Scheme (NAIS) which, until FY 2002-03 was implemented by General Insurance Corporation of India. In addition, AIC also transacts other insurance businesses directly or indirectly concerning agriculture and its allied activities.</string>
    <string name="golden">Golden Agriculture Village Scheme for Karnataka farmers</string>
    <string name="goldenIntro">Gauribidanur, Karnataka, India (03 August 2016) ― Farmers in Karnataka, India are going to see a big transformation in their livelihoods and agricultural productivity. Through a new collaborative initiative, 105 villages will be developed as model villages in the first phase and targeted farmers’ incomes will be increased by 20percent in one year through augmented productivity, diversification and market linkages. In all, 1000 villages will be covered under this scheme. Recognizing the potential for a strong collaboration in dryland agriculture within the framework of their respective development objectives, long-term partners the Government of Karnataka **and International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) along with consortium partners,** today launched a new scheme called Suvarna Krishi Grama Yojane: Transforming agriculture and livelihoods in rural Karnataka (Golden Agriculture Village Scheme) in Hirebidnur town of Karnataka. Hon. Minister of State for Agriculture, Karnataka Mr Krishna Byre Gowda, launched the scheme in the presence of dignitaries, officials and farmers. By actively involving the community in the scheme from the start, the main objective is to transform rural areas by developing an impact oriented participatory model using state of the art technologies. This model can be scaled up for more integrated and sustainable rural development in the state. A comprehensive approach will also be taken by promoting Inclusive Market Oriented Development (IMOD) that links farmers with the markets and builds stable partnerships. The Government of Karnataka decided to implement the Suvarna Krishi Grama Yojane as indicated in the 2015-16 budget speech of Hon’ble Chief Minister of Karnataka in pilot districts and will be scaled-up in a phased manner. The new initiative is expected to provide better livelihoods to thousands living in rural communities in Karnataka through skill development, higher productivity, profitability and increased happiness due to better infrastructure and facilities in their areas.</string>
    <string name="_1_agriculture_loan_general_interest">1.Agriculture loan general interest?</string>
    <string name="answer1">Ans- As per government notification, for crop loans the rate of interest and collateral requirement is as follows: On crop loans: For 2013-14, as per Govt of India notification, crop loans worth Rs. 3 lakh or below would carry an interest rate of 7percent p.a. For those farmers promptly repaying loans, Govt. of India also provide allows interest subvention of 3percent p.a-effectively bringing down interest rate to 4percent p.a. Crop Loans beyond Rs. 3 Lakh, banks charge interest rate as approved by RBI and other conditions as approved by their Board of Directors. As per RBI directive, crop loans till an amount of Rs. 1 lakh require no security. Loans over Rs. 1 lakh may require security as per the lending banks terms and conditions. Post-harvest: Post-harvest loan is available to farmers at a concessional rate of 7percent with interest rate subvention. For farmers availing post-harvest loan against the negotiable warehouse receipts, the banks may charge interest at commercial rates. For land purchase: Banks extend credit for purchase of land within 5 km of the farmers residence at interest rate as determined from time to time. There is no margin for such loans up to Rs 50,000 and amounts higher than this require a margin of 10percent. The land is supposed to mortgaged in favour of the Bank and is considered the security.</string>
    <string name="purchaseLand">2. Can loan be availed for purchase of land?</string>
    <string name="answer2">Yes, banks do extend loans to farmers for purchasing lands. However, banks usually finance purchase of land within a radius of 3 to 5 Kms of their residence or within village boundary.</string>
    <string name="landPurchase">3. Who can apply for such land purchase?</string>
    <string name="answer3">Farmers who own less than 2.5 acres of irrigated land or 5 acres of non-irrigated land, i.e-marginal and small farmers-are eligible to buy land by availing a bank loan. Sharecroppers and tenant farmers can also be covered under the scheme.</string>
    <string name="womenLandPurchase">4. Can loans be availed for purchasing land in the name of women?</string>
    <string name="answer4">Yes, it is possible. As per Govt policy women owning land could lead to their empowerment. Hence, purchase of land in women can be financed and preference can be given to women in distress, SHG members and widows etc.</string>
    <string name="answer5">To encourage institutional borrowing among farmers, banks have relaxed security or collateral for agricultural loans. As per RBI directive, crop loans till an amount of Rs. 1 lakh require no security. Loans over Rs. 1 lakh may require security as per the lending banks terms and conditions. Similarly, there is no margin for loans for purchase of land up to Rs 50,000 and amounts higher than this require a margin of 10percent. The land is supposed to mortgaged in favour of the Bank and is considered the security.</string>
    <string name="_5_how_much_agricultural_loan_can_be_availed_without_any_security">5. How much agricultural loan can be availed without any security?</string>
    <string name="we_will_soon_answer_you_live">We will soon answer you live :) !</string>
    <string name="raithamitra_karnataka_state_department_of_agriculture">Raithamitra: Karnataka State Department of Agriculture</string>
    <string name="krishi_kannada_mobile_applications">Krishi Kannada Mobile Applications</string>
    <string name="find_live_updates_on_agriculture_market_krishi_maratavahini_government_of_india">Find live updates on agriculture market - Krishi Maratavahini- Government of India</string>
</resources>
